Warren Buffett is the most successful investor in the whole world.
The Maximum Wealth Creation
of Warren Buffett Has Been in American
Insurance Companies.  And this health
insurance is a growth sector.
Growth is divisible by the entire insurance
industry.  Cashless reimbursement is also a new
concept.  The potential
to sell health insurance in India is phenomenal.
[Music]
I'll tell you a simple ratio
that will help you easily track these sectors,
their results, their
profit growth, and their overall market
capitalization.  That means this is
an industry where
you can definitely get returns.
And all these companies have been
good wealth creators.
Deepan Mehta is joining us.  Now Director
at Alex Equity [Music]
Deepan Mehta.
We have Deepan Mehta.
Welcome on About Deepan Mehta.
Dipan Mehta
Dipan Mehta.
Deepan Mehta.
Deepan Mehta is with us.
Dipan Mehta in Market Big [Music] Boys.
Hello friends welcome back to Paisa Smart channel
and we are going to
discuss another video with you about another industry
which is quite difficult.
Insurance sector: Till now we were
avoiding this sector because it is very
difficult to explain and also very difficult to
understand.  That is why this sector is generally for
professional investors, that is, fund
managers who have big
analyst teams, generally only they
can track this sector well, value it
and then invest.
But I am so happy that we have so many
viewers.  He has specifically
written in our comment section that please Mr. Mehta
Deepan ji, please do analysis on the insurance sector.
Please do a presentation on the insurance sector as the king of the sector.
Bring me an episode.  So on
popular demand, after a lot of hard work, I am going to
discuss the insurance industry with you.
Raja podcast of this particular sector.  But this sector is quite
difficult.  Complex and finally As
Usual We Will Announce Who Is The Sector's
King.  And you will definitely be surprised.
This announcement of our sector, the
company we have chosen, that is a perfect
play on the entire insurance sector.
So if you do
n't want to get into the complexities of the insurance industry, you
can simply buy this company and you will have
a great play on the entire insurance
sector.  But, the first question that arises is
whether this insurance sector is
so important for investors or not?  In my opinion, the
insurance sector is very important for you.
Firstly, you are buying insurance.
If you are buying a car or a
motorcycle then you are buying
insurance.  Many of our investors are
buying medical insurance.  If
your medical insurance is not health then
you should definitely buy it.  And then they are also
buying insurance for life, that is,
you are buying life insurance policies.
And many enterprises which are
small scale units are also
buying insurance from fire and
protection.  If you have taken a loan from the bank, then the
bank will definitely insist that you must get an
insurance policy for your
factories, for establishments, for your
shops so that if there is a loss, then that loss is getting
covered by the insurance company.
That is why the entire activity of the insurance sector and those who buy insurance is
very important.  And from an
investor's perspective, the insurance
sector is also very important.  Because our
economy, the Indian economy, is a growth
economy.  The average growth rate here is 10-12%
in nominal terms.
Because of this, insurance opportunities are quite
good for the insurance companies.
Therefore, I think
we can see steady growth in the listed insurance companies.
That is why if you are a long
term investor and want to study compounding
business then you should definitely do
some study in the insurance sector.  You
should increase your knowledge.  You should listen to podcasts like ours.
And then you may look at
identifying the right opportunity to
invest in the insurance sector.  Look,
I would
not like to go into so much detail about what insurance exactly is, but all I can say is that
broadly this sector is
highly regulated.  Insurance Regulated
Development Authority (IRDA) is its regulator
and it has made many strict rules.
Due to which the
growth of this industry has been very good and if
you notice, there has hardly been any
systematic, sorry,
systematic risk in the insurance industry. The
insurance companies are
audited in great detail as to what policies they are selling,
that too is IRDA or other
regulators, they look at it very closely and
approve it and if anything is
anomalous then immediately they are brought to the
notice.  Many of the products have also become
quite standardized.  That means
you can do Apple to Apple comparison.
And this is the reason why there is a lack of innovation
in this sector, which according to me is
a bit of a risk factor.  There
is a little disappointment.  But what we are
getting in front of that is we are getting a nice well
regulated sector so that the risk of the investor is
protected.  Getting a sector
which is absolutely a great play on the
entire economy as well.  If the economy improves,
if people buy more cars and houses,
if they are setting up factories and
offices, or if they feel that going ahead their
health care expenses are going to increase, or if
they feel that they must get
protection for their life as well.  There has been a
lot of maturity there too.  So, this
demand for insurance products is
going to keep on gradually increasing more
and less in line with the GDP growth
rate and even higher.  And in this industry, it is
not so easy that a new company
comes and sets up and you can easily start your work.
It is not like the
banking industry and the NBFC
industry that there are 100s and 100s of
banks and NBFCs that can
start lending business.  There are only 1520 insurance
companies in India where they have to
focus and it is not easy to
get a license to start an insurance company,
so this also creates a little comparative edge
for insurance stocks and for
shareholders of insurance companies.  Let us
look at the companies that we have selected, our entire list is the universe of the listed companies, and
classify which type of
insurance companies these are.  Then we will discuss a little about the different
segments of insurance.
Then we will give you some more knowledge as regards
what are the newses
and how should you look at valuing the
industry?  And we will also discuss why it is so complex.
And of course, at the
end, we will announce the disc, we will announce the king of our sector.
So
please watch this video till the end.  It
is very important for you.  Because I am sure the
thought must have come to your mind that you should be
looking at buying insurance companies.  But it
is very difficult to understand and track them and my effort will be that
in the next few minutes I will give you some such
formulas and some such thumb rules in an easy way
so that you can understand this insurance industry and
insurance stocks in a better way
and if you want to invest then
you can invest wisely.
So let's pay attention to this
particular slide where we have included the
insurance companies which are listed in the space,
here we have included these insurance companies in our list.
So broadly speaking, the insurance sector we would like to
divide into three particular
categories.  The first category is General
Insurance where we have selected the General
Insurance Company i.e. GECR,
Go Digital General, ICICI LB and New India
Insurance, so these are our four General
Insurance Companies.  In this also,
GIC is coming into reinsurance, so
their business model is a little different as
compared to GD Digit ICIC and New India
Insurance, then we will focus on our two listed health
insurance companies which is
Neeva BUPA Health which
is a new listing and Star Health
Insurance where the legendary Rakesh
Unionwala has a huge stake.  Then there are the
life insurance companies HDFC L,
ICICI Pro, LIC of India, Max Finance
Services and SBI Lite, so
we will discuss these companies a little bit and these
companies are RB listed in the
last few years and so I think they must have
invested in many portfolios.  So
please pay special attention to this also.  And finally, when we are
discussing the insurance
sector, we have included two companies which are focused on
providing insurance services, which
are
Medi Assist and PV Fintech. Let
me explain a little bit about what these categories within
the insurance industry actually do
?  So our first category of
insurance companies is general
insurance companies.  The General Insurance
Company is the company which is providing all
insurance products except life
insurance.  What is the government's strategy? The
government's thinking is that if you are doing
life insurance, then you should do only
life insurance.  In the same company,
you cannot sell general insurance products there.
And if you are doing general
insurance work then you
cannot sell life insurance products there.
Therefore, the big groups are
setting up separate companies for general
insurance and separate companies for life
insurance.  Because the product is
very different.  Which is life insurance
that is providing a big insurance
outflow.  If someone takes your life,
they pay your family.
They pay insurance claims.  And they are
also providing savings
products.  Their products are
generally multiyear products.
But general insurance is an annual feature.
If you have taken a general insurance policy then
you have to renew it every year.
So these general insurance companies are a
separate category.  Their operations are also different.
Their valuation model is also different.
Their business model is of course completely
different.  So if you have bought a new car
then you have to buy motor insurance.  Every
year you have to renew it again.
If you have bought a house or a flat and
if you need insurance for
fire or earthquake, then for that also you have to
buy an annual insurance policy which has to be
renewed from time to time.   The
government has insisted that these
insurance companies should also provide
crop insurance.  And then the last one
in general insurance is medical care
Medicare i.e. health insurance.
Of course there are companies which are focused
and doing only health insurance.  But
all these general insurance companies also have
a very strong and vibrant
health insurance division.  And this health
insurance is a growth sector.
Growth is divisible by the entire insurance
industry.  Because awareness
is gradually increasing.  Your hospital bills are
running into lakhs right now.  It is proving very expensive.
Therefore, every household, every family,
every employer is thinking that please first consider the biggest
important expense
of any family that is buying medical
insurance policies.  So you have to buy it
so that if you get sick, have an
accident, get hospitalized
, have to undergo an operation, or have to undergo any medical
treatment, then you are being
reimbursed by the insurance companies.  Otherwise,
these hospital bills can eat into
the savings of a household.  Therefore,
in my opinion, if you do not have health
insurance, medical insurance,
then please
buy this medical insurance tomorrow itself.
It is a great protection from any
emergency expenses on the medical side which may come
to you.  So as I said, these
general insurance companies are focused
largely on these particular categories.  And
if you look at it, according to me, the highest growth is
in health insurance.
And then the second one is motor insurance.
Why Motor Insurance?  You've seen that
in the post-GST There's Been a Huge
Surgeon Vol.  For every new vehicle that
is sold, the insurance agency or the
car dealer gives it to you after purchasing it,
hence we are seeing good demand there
and then if you
buy a car or a motorcycle, then you have to
renew it every year, so a steady cash
flow is created for the insurance companies,
after that there is of course the health
insurance as I talked about for you
and then there is also marine insurance, that is, the
ships are insured
and then of course there is crop
insurance.  If agriculture fails,
insurance can be available there also.
And there are many innovative insurance
products too.  As you know,
if a cricket match is being held in any country
or any city,
you can take insurance for that also.  So that if the
cricket match gets washed out then the
insurance company will compensate you for that
particular damage which has occurred.
Because you have to return the ticket money.
Your event has been cancelled.
So even concerts and even cricket
matches spotting events you can get an
insurance cover on that also.  So there are a
lot of opportunities in this entire general insurance sector.  This industry is
comparative and also regulated.  But
its growth rate is steady and I think
it is linked very closely to the
overall economic activity and the acquisition
of new assets.  Yes, if
you buy any new asset, be it a car or a
motorcycle, a house, a shop or an office, it
is necessary to take insurance for everything.  And somehow it is regulatory
required also.  Therefore,
we have seen very good growth rates in this industry.
And this business,
I think, is a business of study cash flow.
Actually this entire infrastructure industry,
study cash flow business.  So here you can
get good returns.
One special thing I would like to tell you is that this is
a very
interesting observation or a very
interesting special thing in this industry.  That is, have
you ever wondered what these general insurance
companies do after taking your premium
?  So the premium that you pay for years and years,
this is the income that comes to them that they are
investing in the market which could be
day market, could be equity market also
and other day products also and the
interest income that they get also becomes their income
and their biggest expense is the
claims which they pay out model you understand it is
quite simple you pay the premium, this
premium is invested
in investment products where it can give
good returns anywhere
from 6% to 10-11% also and this money
which comes every month, every year, that
investment can also be done for long term
but if a claim comes then they are
paying out that claim as well and this
claim becomes the biggest expense
after marketing for these insurance
companies and
we will discuss this whole thing in detail when we come
to the valuation segment of
this video.  Please be patient with this.
But broadly income is premium received,
investment income, expenses are claims
and expenses is the marketing cost which
goes into selling these insurance
policies.  So, this was the
business model of these summary general insurance companies.  Health
insurance is also the same business model.  General
Insurance.  As I said, the general
insurance company here is
shown on the screen as they are anyway into health
insurance.  But there are some companies
whose thinking is such that their focus is
totally on health insurance and medical
insurance because its
demand is going to be very high in India.  Its
requirements are definitely going to improve
because we are a very large
population.  Medical costs are quite
high here.  There are many low income mid income
families who cannot afford a lot of
medical expenses.  That is why the
entire
focus of these companies in this segment is on health insurance.  A
lot of innovation has been done here.  You may know that
cashless reimbursement is also a new concept.  That means the
health insurance
companies have tied up with key
hospital chains and key hospitals in
your city as well.  Therefore, if you have an
accident or need any medical
treatment, you can get admitted without paying any money.
You can be admitted.  You can take
your treatment and whatever
money is there, the insurance company can
pay it directly to the hospital.  So there's a
little bit of innovation here I think
and a little bit of care to be taken.  This marketing
of health insurance policies also
happens in a slightly different way and
you have to follow many steps there.  For example,
if you have purchased a health insurance policy,
the health insurance company
will insist on doing a medical checkup also.  There are a lot of
interesting and nuances in the processing of the claims that come after that.  There are many
different steps
which are also to be taken to ensure that the
claim you have submitted is genuine
and you are not overpaid.  So in
this health insurance segment, there are
two companies over here, Niva BUPA and
Star Health, their processes are also good according to me
because health
insurance is a highly under penetrated
segment in India.  Yes, I repeat, the
potential to sell health insurance in India is
phenomenal.  The point is that families have
resistance.  As awareness gradually
increases, more and more families will buy health
insurance.  And those who already have health
insurance will like to
increase their claim amount.  Many times we have
seen that the family's health insurance
policy is worth one or two lakhs and when they understand
how important it is, they are
gradually increasing it to 2 lakhs, 5 lakhs,
10 lakhs and also take a top-up policy
so that if any illness occurs in their family and
any member has to be hospitalized, then at
least they do not have to
dip the savings of the family. So, this
segment is an interesting segment.  It is
a niche segment within the insurance
industry and as an investor, you should
definitely focus on it if you are a long term investor.
Let us
move ahead and come to the most difficult part
of the insurance industry
which is the life insurance companies.  Here
we have seen that our selection is
HDFC L ICICI 2, Life Insurance
Corporation Max India and SBI L and
all these companies have been good wealth
creators.  So it is not that the returns were
not good.  They've Been Good Wealth
Creators.  After the IPO, it has given them
good returns.  But
sir, it is very difficult for investors to analyze these companies.  Unlike other
insurance companies Repeating unlike other
insurance companies which are in health
care and medical insurance where we can still
value on price earnings multiple or price to book basis.  We can
not use the same method.  We
cannot use the same method for valuation of
life insurance companies.  There is a lot of fluctuation in their results and
profits,
and their entire
accounting system is also very
difficult to understand.  He
takes many tests there.  Behind those assumptions, there are
some norms of IRDA, i.e. the regulator,
and their entire business is very
complex in
understanding when it comes to the
accounting level.  Money is business simple.
What does End of the Day do?  It takes the money from you
and then can pay you out after a few years
or in between if you die then it will
give that large
claim amount to your family as well.  Such
on the place of it looks simple.  But
how much premium can you charge?  How much do
you need to invest and where?  How
is your policy structured?  How much
marketing margin can you afford?  How much
minimum payout do you have to give?  This is a
big deal on all things.  There are many regulations and rules.
Because of this, there
is less innovation in this industry.  Because what the government
believes is that you are selling a trust.  You
are selling, you are taking money from the
public and assuring them that you will compensate them
in the event of death.  You are
assuring them that after 5, 10, 15, 20 years
you will get steady payout or you may get
lumpsum payout.  So
what returns should you get?  That should be in
line with long term returns in an
industry.  For this reason, this sector is
highly regulated.  It is also quite complex.
But in the end,
I will tell you a simple ratio due to which you will be
able to track this sector easily.   You will be
able to value this sector easily
and if you want to invest after careful consideration or
you are already invested then
we will also explain how to monitor it, so
please watch this video till the end, so this was
our discussion on the life insurance company, a
little more is left because the
interesting part is coming in the
valuation part of this thing, but
still this business is a very good
compounding business because once you have
bought the policy then your commitment is made
for paying the premium for sometime
3 years, 5 years, 10 years also.  This means that
your premium will have to increase every year.
So that becomes the income of these companies.
So as I explained,
what is the income of life insurance companies?
Premium income, investment income, their
payout is these claims.  Similarly for the life
insurance companies, the premium they receive also
becomes their income.  But, the
premium that comes with it, they are investing
it.  Part of the investment gas is
shared with the policy holders as well.   Yes,
this does not happen in general insurance
that the investment income that comes is
not shared with the policy holders.  But there are
some products in the life
insurance segment where if the
insurance company has taken money from you
on premium, especially in long term
premium policies which are
long term life policies, it
invests some of the money there
and the benefit of that investment is also passed on to you.  These
policies are non-participating policies
and can give very good returns on a
long term basis.  But there are some
products where you only
get protection.  That means you
paid the premium, at the end of the term
you will get a fixed bullet payout or
you will get a pension and in between if you
die then your family can get the claim.
But you have no right on this premium income
which the insurance
company invests.  So, there
are two-three types of broad policies.  But end
of the day business model appears to be simple.
Accounting and valuation is very
complex.  Moving ahead,
we have also included two insurance services companies
in this list.  The reason for this is
that we found their business model quite
interesting.  They have got good
potential because if you are
positive in the insurance sector then the prospects of these companies should
remain good.  So the
first company that has been selected is
Mediservice.  This company is
processing the medical claims.  That means
you have purchased health insurance.  You have
purchased a medical claim.  You have been
hospitalized.  When you have submitted the bill,
the insurance company is sending
that particular claim and that medical bill to
MediAssist and MediAssist is then
understanding it, analyzing it.  Making
sure that the documentation is proper and that the
expenditure incurred is genuine.  After
checking all this, it then sends a notification to the insurance company
that you have to
pay this much money.  This is not justified.  It is
not that much allowed.  You can deduct this much.
If you have ever submitted a claim for processing,
you must have interacted with Medi Assist or
any other TPA third party associate
third party company in
terms of
passing your mediclaim.  This company
interacts directly with the policy
holders to understand whether
their claim is exactly what it is?  Why did they have to be
hostelized?  Whether the amount spent
was correct or not and then they are passing the
claim and passing it on to the insurance
company.  So it is a very interesting model.  If
your view on health insurance is positive then of course
this MediAssist will do it should do reasonably
well.
This company has made many acquisitions.  And I think the
prospects of this company should
remain good going forward.  And then there is PB Fintech
which is the owner and operator of a very
very popular portal called
Policy Baa. You must have heard about Policy Baa but PV
Fintech is the holding company for
Policy Baa and what happens on Policy Bazaar is that they are
selling all types of insurance
policies and also they are selling all
sorts of loan products also so their
main job is selling. They are not an
insurance company but here you
can go and compare the products of all the insurance companies.  It will help
you identify.  Their agents will
help you identify the correct
insurance policy for you and will
enable you to make a payment for that
insurance policy as well.  This is actually what an
insurance agent does.
As many policies are sold on Policy Bazaar, the
insurance companies are giving commission and they are
giving marketing income to Policy
Bazaar and Policy Bazaar is using that
income to sell more and more policies.  That is why
its business model is also quite interesting.
It is a nice platform company and I
think you should definitely track this company.
Because on the whole insurance has to be sold,
then this is the only
company which is India's largest insurance
selling port.  So, this was our discussion on
all the various types of insurance
companies.  And in a very simple way I have tried
to explain to you the business models of these companies.
What is his income?
What are their expenses?  I have
tried to explain that to you also.  So I hope you have
like this particular video till now.
Because then you can easily understand
what is the exact work of the insurance company
?  What is his income?
What are their expenses?  Let's move ahead and discuss the
growth rates of these companies.
So let's go on to
the next slide which is growth rate.
We have sorted these companies on the basis of their profit growth in the last 3 years.
And the highest profit growth has come
through LIC followed by New India Assurance
, GDIT, Niva BUPA, GIC, so on
and so on.  But if you see, there is a very
good growth rate for the insurance
companies.  The average growth rate has been
around 38% and so even if you take out LIC
and New India and the bottom two, still the
average growth rate has been around 30% in the
profits of the companies.  That means, in a
sense, this is definitely a growth industry
because there is good profit growth
here.  But you have to understand that if you
are an investor then there can be a lot of volatility
in earnings here.  This is not a
stable business.  There are banks, cement or
other pharma companies.  Steady 15% to
10% growth occurs.  It is not like that here.
Sometimes there is loss also.  Sometimes the profit
increases two-three times.  Sometimes it even decreases by 70-80%.
We will discuss the reason for that.
But at the end of the day on a long term basis
on a trailing failure basis the results are good.
Profit growth is good.
Let us understand why there is so much volatility
in earnings.  The reason for this is
that if you are a general insurance company, then the
payout of claims is very very
uncertain.  If there is an
earthquake or heavy rain
storms and something happens that
destroys many vehicles in your city
or something like this happens, a
natural disaster, then suddenly the claims
increase for the insurance companies
due to which the losses increase and hence you are seeing
a drop in the
profitability. When it comes to the
life insurance companies, there are so many assumptions as to
how much can you allocate from
investment income to the policy holder and
how many policy holders there are, how many
deaths have occurred, how many renewals do they do, it is
quite complex, that is why
we are seeing a lot of volatility in the
earnings of even the life insurance
companies, but in our two medical
services companies, Medi Assist and
PB Fintech, we have seen that the
revenues and profits are generally quite stable,
but it is not that, it is not a
high growth sector, it is not a
slow moving sector.  Because on a point to
point basis on a long time frame,
we have seen that in the long run their results, their
profit growth and their overall market
capitalization remain quite good.  Let us
discuss what the long term returns have been
in this industry and here
you will see as I said that
PV Fintech which is in insurance services,
the returns over three years have been the
best at 64% followed by general
insurance which is 46% and
according to us the best insurance company is
Max Financial its growth rate
was about 30% and otherwise also I think
returns I am talking about stock
market compound returns over the three
years are pretty decent for the
insurance companies generally in line with the
returns given in the market by Sussex
and Nifty.  That means there is an industry
where you can definitely
get returns.  If you invest for three, four or five years, you can
get good returns.
So we have made this slide especially so that
you do not ignore this sector.
You should try to understand this sector a little.
Good winners can come here too.
Study Winners May Come and
Mostant Mostant Industrial Perspective
This is a defensive industry.  Why
are you defensive?  Because the economy improves and
declines.  Your income increases and decreases.
But the basic insurance that you have to
buy, the commitment that you have made,
you have to pay it, you have to pay it.
Therefore there is a high degree of stability
in the cash flows of these companies.  So in a way it becomes
a defensive sector.  And if
we have seen in the entire market that the whole
market is correcting big time, the
insurance companies generally their correction remains less.
I am a low beta stock and I would like to
share another secret with you
which is very dear to me.  So you must have
heard about Warren Buffett who is the
most successful investor in the whole world.  He achieved
his best returns
in American insurance companies.  So
please do not underestimate these insurance companies in terms
of their
capability to deliver returns.  This has been
proven by Warren Buffett himself who has
generated phenomenal returns over the
past 40-50 years as well.  So this was our
discussion on the returns.  Let's move ahead
and discuss valuations.
You have to pay special attention to this because when it comes
to insurance companies, their
valuation is done in a slightly different way.
So generally, the valuations of general insurance or
health insurance companies are done on the
basis of PE multiple
and here we have highlighted
that these are the PE multiples of these companies
and on that basis
you can value it as a normal any other business.
So here if you see then the
cheapest company is General Insurance and
after that we are seeing New India
Insurance also means that the PSU
companies are valued more attractively
cheaper than the private companies and of course the
most expensive are the two health care
companies which is Neeva BUPA and Star
Insurance because investors believe
that its potential is very good and there
is a new generation insurance company Gold
Digit, its valuation is also very
expensive because its growth is
very good and they are steadily
increasing the market share.  Still ICICI
is LBD.  Its valuations are also quite
reasonable.  And of course there is the
new India Insurance.  These are the
valuation ratios for these companies.  If we
move ahead and the
pre-multiple of the insurance companies, which I
will highlight here in absolute
orange, you have to completely ignore it,
according to me.  Because we cannot value
this insurance company based on their
price earning multiple.  These companies are
globally valued on their embedded
value.  Now a new concept has come up called
embedded value.  Difficult to explain but
it is of book value type.  That is, all the
policies sold when they are actually
terminated and the payouts are made.
So its residual value is
calculated after taking some assumptions.  And
this calculation is the embed
value.  It is God's grace that these
insurance companies are announcing their
embedded value every quarter and we do
not need to calculate it.
That's why when you track and understand life insurance companies, the
first thing I look for in the investor
release is the embedded value.  And the ratio between embedding
value and market capitalization, which is
basically market capitalization divided
by embedding value, is the ratio we have to
keep a special eye on and that is how we compare these
companies and that is how we can
figure out whether the embedding value or
the valuation is cheap or
expensive.  This embeded value keeps
increasing gradually.  We have seen
that whenever there is growth in these insurance
companies, especially life insurance
companies, their embedded value keeps going up
by 15%, 20%, 30% like that.  That is,
as the embedded value increases, automatically if you
study the ratio of market cap to EV embedded value, then
as the embedded value increases, you get
returns in the stock price.   For
example, if the company's embedded
value is 100 and its market
capitalization is 200, then the market cap to
EV is two.  If in 3 years this embed
value goes from 200 to 300 and this
ratio of market cap to embed value remains at 12, then
automatically your
value becomes ₹600.
So this was the rough calculation why you should look at the
embed value.  I will
repeat it again because it is a bit complicated.
You should understand that the embed value of the company is
100.  Its market capitalization
is 200.  When you invested, its embed
value was two.  What happens after 3 years?
After 3 years, if this embed value which is 100 becomes
150.  But this
market cap to embedded value remains
constant at two.  Then definitely the
market cap of this company will be 300, which means
you have got 50% appreciation from 200 to 300
in your stock price.
So the embedded value is like the book
value, it could be looking at a steady
concern ratio which keeps on going up.   So that is why
you should keep a special eye on the embedded values ​​of these insurance companies.
And I would like to highlight this.  The
embed value of HDFC is
2.66.  ICICI Approval is 1.72 Times.
LIC is going ever discount to its embedded
value at 72 times, Max Financial at 1.98 and
SBI Life at 2.43 times.  So as you'll
see, the embedded values ​​of the
private companies are more or less in that
range of about 2.2 times also.  For this
reason, whenever you want to analyze a life insurance
company, you should immediately
go to market cap to embedded value.
If it is around two or less than two, then I
think it is reasonably valued and if
you look at it, the embedded value of Max Life
is attractive at 1.98
times.  You may ask why the embed value of LIC is
only 72, there are many reasons
why we don't need to go into it at this
point of time.  But there is considerable
scope for this ratio to increase for LIC.
That's why this is an interesting proposition.
If this ratio of LIC, i.e. market cap
to embedded value, increases then
definitely its stock price can outperform.
Finally, let's look at the
valuation of Meddi Assist and PB
Fintech.  So here you will see Medi
Assist going at 40 times and PB Fintech
is going at 26 times.  Because basically
it is a platform company.  It is like a
fintech company.  That is why its
valuation and its fancy are always a little
higher here.  So this was our complete
discussion on insurance companies.  In such a short
time, I have explained to you many nuns, many
remedies on the insurance
companies.  And I hope I have been able to make
you interested in the insurance companies.  And
if you want to understand more then please you can
go deep into each company.  These companies
also have very interesting investor presentations.
And if you do
n't understand any terminology, there is of course the
Internet and Chat GPT to
explain that particular terminology to
you.  Before I leave,
I would like to present to you a special slide about this company, LIC.
So, please
keep an eye on this.  I am coming to an
end, please give me some more time.  So this
figure in orange that you see here is the
proportion of savings in
life insurance.  Despite so much
investment in equity market mutual funds,
the average household still
invests around 18%
in life insurance policies.  So this is a
very positive point for the overall
insurance companies.  So you have to pay special attention to this also
and when you analyze insurance companies, there are
many
abbreviations which I have presented here.  It
is a little important to understand these.
But like I said market cap to
embedded value for an insurance company is the
most important thing and sorry I forgot one more thing
the real ratio for a general insurance
company.  Sorry, we have to go back to our
valuation.  Sorry viewers.  So here
we have not discussed this combined ratio.
So let us
discuss that a little bit.  So this combined
ratio is the total claims paid
divided by the income.
This combined ratio excludes the
investment gains made by the general
insurance company.  And
the lower this combined ratio, the more successful the
insurance company becomes.  And if
you see here, the combined
ratio of GIC is 107.  The number of Go digits is 108.  New
ICS is 103.  New India Ashes is 116,
Neevapa is 103 and Star Health is 99.  So the
lower the combined ratio, that shows how
profitable the insurance businesses are
and the higher the combined ratio,
that shows how much dependency there is on the
investment gas.  So if a general
insurance company sells policies by doing good
risk management and good assessment, then
definitely its
combined ratio will be low and if the combined
ratio is low then basically the company is more
profitable than its peer group. It is a bit
complex and I hope you can go deeper into it
by studying the combined ratio
but this is not a valuation ratio, it is
only an efficiency ratio which you should definitely
keep in mind.  As we look at
return on capital employed and return on
investment,
this combined ratio is very important for general insurance companies.
This fluctuates depending
upon the claim which they pay out.  But at the end of
the day, if the trend is down, if it is steady,
that is very, very positive for these
companies.  Come on, it's time to announce the
king of the over sector.  And in this
we will declare the king of the sector in a little different way
because as I
said there are the general insurance companies, there are
the life insurance companies and there are
the insurance services
providers.  So it is important to discuss with you the king of these sectors.
So according to us, in the general insurance
segment, the king of the sector is
ICICI LBRD whose valuation, as you
can see, is around 35 times.  Decent
performer.  The special thing about this company is
that they are very focused on
profitability.  They are very focused
on selling the right insurance policies and
making sure that their claims losses are
always low.  We have seen
that many times they have
avoided crop insurance because it is
not profitable.  So I would say ICICI LBAT
is a great stock in the general insurance
segment.
If you look at life insurance,
our top pick would be SBI Life Insurance
which is trading at 1.98 times market
cap to EV and this company is a very
aggressive company.  It is part of the SBI
Group and because of that they get a lot of good
inquiries.  They can easily sell
over their policies to SBI
customers as well.  So, this is our
king of the sector or sub-sector.  But
for the entire insurance industry
according to us the king of the sector has to be
PB Fintech.  As I said in the beginning,
if you have to buy only one share.  Only
one stock has to be tracked.  This
is not a recommendation.  This is just advice
on strategy, you only have to track one company.
Which is a play on the entire
insurance sector.  That company is
PB Fintech.  Because insurance has to be sold.
As insurance policies
are sold, this company gets commission income and
its business runs on the basis of that commission income.
They are able to pay for the expenses and they are
once who are actually owning the customers.   The
special thing about this platform company is that it is
owned by the customer.  They are in direct
contact with the customer.  That is why their
value addition is the highest.  So one
single company in this sector ka raja is PV
Fintech but in general insurance we would go
with ICICI Almarg and in life insurance
we would go with SBI Life as the sub sector ka
raja and then of course PV Fintech is the
overall sector ka raja.  But you should definitely keep an eye on
our small company, Medi SS Services.
This can also
become a study performance.  And it is a
great play on medical insurance.   I
gave you many ideas because the
industry is such that there is a lot of vibrancy here.  There
are a lot of opportunities.  That is why we have presented three-four
companies before you.  These
are not recommendations.  You have to
go deeper into it.  If you want to buy.
You have to understand them and their business model a little better.  Don't take it like that.
Let
us finally come to the risk factors.
So the biggest risk factor
in the insurance industry is government regulation.
Government regulation is there to protect
the policy holders.  The most
important objective of IDA is to
protect the interests of the policy holders.  Therefore, many
such rules come into force which have a
negative impact on the profitability of insurance companies.  So according to me,
regulation is the biggest risk factor
for the insurance company on a broader
basis.  If we look individually or sub-sector wise,
if the claims increase then that
definitely becomes a big problem and a
risk factor for insurance companies like it happened
in Covid.  Many
people lost their lives due to Covid.  There were also policy
holders of all these life insurance
companies and life insurance companies were there to
make huge payouts due to these deaths.
So this becomes a risk factor
for the insurance companies.
We have seen that whenever any such incident happens
, any catastrophe occurs, there is a flood
or an earthquake
or any such thing happens due to which
there is a huge destruction of
property.  So at that time, the
premiums of these general insurance companies, their
payouts and their claims
increase.  This has a negative impact on their profitability.
So
sharp increase in claims for any
external event is a big risk factor
for the insurance industry.  But if
you look at the trends of 5, 10, 15, 20 years, then
generally it gets normalized.
So, you have to keep a close eye on these two major risk factors
and if you are a long
term investor then I think this sector
offers good potential for giving decent
returns.  Lastly thank you so much for subscribing to support our channel.
This was a complicated
trick which I did easily and in a
simplistic way I have been able to
explain to you.  And this
is our objective.  It is our endeavor to
present to you the complexities of the stock market in an easy manner.  Explain it to you
so that you can be a more knowledgeable investor.
Thank you This podcast
all registered registration number 1N4787
in provide incast education only consider
investment investment security
market marketly
documently reading from.